recyclebank.com 2017-02-06

# Privacy Policy

_Last Updated February 24, 2015_

**Recyclebank's Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy is provided by RecycleRewards, Inc. and its wholly-owned subsidiaries, including, Recyclebank, LLC and Recycle Rewards Limited, which are referred within the policy collectively as “Recyclebank”, “we”, “us” and/or “our”.

**_Introduction:_**

OUR MISSION is to motivate individuals and communities to realize a world without waste. As such, we bring together individuals from around the world to participate in our various programs and get rewarded for taking every day green actions through our Recyclebank Rewards Program. In order to authenticate and empower our Rewards Program, Recyclebank collects and stores certain types of information about our members to verify identity and activity in the Rewards Program along with enabling us to communicate with our members directly, and in turn customize their experience with us.

Recyclebank is committed to protecting our members' privacy.  The following Privacy Policy explains how and why we collect certain types of information, and how we act on your behalf to protect the privacy and security of that information. Below we provide insight on the types of information Recyclebank collects independent of and also through this website (the “Site”),  www.OneTwine.com, an affiliated website owned and operated by Recyclebank (“One Twine”), and how we use it.  In addition, this policy discusses the different programs offered by Recyclebank independent of or through this Site which comprise the Recyclebank Rewards Program and further how member information is integrated into each member's account with Recyclebank.

Please read this Privacy Policy and send us any questions, concerns and suggestions you may have. To contact us, please see the contact information provided below under “Contact Us”.

**_What Recyclebank's Privacy Policy Covers:_**

Click on any of the questions below for the answers you need on everything relating to our Privacy Policy.

  1. What information does Recyclebank collect?
  2. Why does Recyclebank collect information about you and how do we use it? 
  3. Who does Recyclebank share your information with and why? 
  4. How can you change your privacy preferences or account information?
  5. What information is collected through integration with third party services? 
  6. Third party links and websites.
  7. Are there any other issues to consider?
  8. Updates to the Privacy Policy.

### 1\. What Information Does Recyclebank Collect?

To participate in any of our Programs we may need to know your home address or contact address, contact phone number, email address which we receive through various sources as detailed below. We may also require you to create a unique password and security PIN and question and agree that Recyclebank may record certain information about you. From time to time participants will be asked for PII such as demographics (age, income, etc.), psychographics (what you like to purchase, etc.) and interests. Submission of this information is entirely voluntary and may qualify you for additional reward Points earning opportunities. In addition, Recyclebank records content, such as text, images, pictures, and profile information, which you submit or upload to the Site or any other Recyclebank platform such as an off-site mobile application or social media platform. User images and screen names that you upload to the Site or select will be displayed in order to identify you, both to yourself and to other participants. To best serve you, we may combine this information with data that is publicly available and data that we receive from other reputable sources whose policies meet the Direct Marketing Association's privacy standards.

Before you begin participation in any of our Programs, you will need to activate or register your account on either the Site or via a Recyclebank partner site. The method for activating or registering your account will vary by Rewards Program. Recyclebank does not rent or sell members' PII or program activity with anyone without a member's express consent. We reserve the right to report to law enforcement agencies any activities that we, in good faith, believe to be unlawful.

#### _A. Information You Provide:_

In order for you to participate in the Recyclebank Rewards Program (which includes our home recycling programs, and many other contests and activities) you first must become a Recyclebank Member and agree to the [Recyclebank Membership Agreement](http://www.recyclebank.com/about-us/membership-agreement1). Through this registration process you provide us with:

(i) Personally identifiable information (“PII”) such as your name, street address, phone number, or e-mail address, which we use to enroll you in our program and communicate with you.

(ii) Information about you and your household (such as your age, education, household composition), which we use to verify your eligibility for our program as well as to provide a more personalized experience

(iii) Online Profile Information.  Online profiles are created for Members who use the Site to participate in the Recyclebank Rewards Program. By creating an online profile on our Site, we also allow Members to submit on a voluntary basis certain personal information about themselves they wish to share through their online Recyclebank profile (such as hobbies and interests, pictures, text descriptions, friends, and other profile information similar to other social networking communities.) Your online profile can be updated through our preferences center on our Site, various mobile applications, and our Customer Care Call Center.

Submission of this information described above in (i), (ii) and (iii) is entirely voluntary.  By voluntarily providing us with your PII and/or any other information, you are consenting to our use of it in accordance with this Privacy Policy.  Take notice that all unsolicited information (other than your PII) that you provide to Recyclebank through our Site or through other means (such as by posting to any public areas of the Site or sending us ideas for new services or modifications to our services) is deemed non-confidential and we are free to reproduce, use, disclose, and distribute any of this unsolicited information to others without limitation or attribution, in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

#### _B. Information Provided About You From Other Sources:_

Your participation in some of Recyclebank's programs, such as the Home Recycling Program, may lead to us to receiving certain additional information about you through third parties. This information may originate from:

  * your waste or recycling hauling company 
  * your municipality (with respect to US residents)
  * other government entities
  * partner websites you access through our Site or retailers where you can earn or redeem Recyclebank Reward Points 
  * social media and social networking sites like Facebook or Twitter that you have opted to link to your Recyclebank online account through the Site.

As detailed above, in order for you to participate in any of our Programs we will need to know certain information about you which we receive directly from you or through various sources. We may also require you to create a unique password and security PIN and question and agree that Recyclebank may record certain information about you. From time to time participants will be asked for PII such as demographics (age, income, etc.), psychographics (what you like to purchase, etc.) and interests. Submission of this information is entirely voluntary and may qualify you for additional reward Points earning opportunities. In addition, Recyclebank records content, such as text, images, pictures, and profile information, which you submit or upload to the Site or any other Recyclebank platform such as an off-site mobile application or social media platform. User images and screen names that you upload to the Site or select will be displayed in order to identify you, both to yourself and to other participants. To best serve you, we may combine this information with data that is publicly available and data that we receive from other reputable sources whose policies meet the Direct Marketing Association's privacy standards.

Before you begin participation in any of our Programs, you will need to activate or register your account on either the Site or via a Recyclebank partner site. The method for activating or registering your account will vary by Program. Recyclebank does not rent or sell members' PII or program activity with anyone without a member's express consent. We reserve the right to report to law enforcement agencies any activities that we, in good faith, believe to be unlawful.

#### _C. Website Browsing Information & Cookies:_

When you visit our Site, we track information to assist us administering the Site and analyzing Site usage. This information includes:

  * your Internet Protocol (IP) address,
  * cookies (as further detailed below),
  * the state or country from which you access the Site,
  * date and time of your visit to the Site,
  * the kind of browser or computer you use,
  * name of your Internet service provider,
  * web pages from which you link to our Site or go to from our Site, or
  * the webpages within our Site you view when visiting our Site. 

Additionally, when you access our Site by using a mobile device, we may collect information about your location in order to enable certain features of our mobile applications.

Recyclebank uses third party technology, Google Analytics, in order to track session data. Google Analytics adheres to industry best privacy principles with respect to its data collection practices. Recyclebank does not provide Google with any PII as part of using Google Analytics. Further information about the Google Analytics privacy principles can be found at <http://www.google.com/intl/en/analytics/learn/privacy.html>.

Further, Recyclebank uses Google AdWords as a remarketing service which enables Recyclebank to advertise to previous visitors on our Site via third party websites (including Google). When you visit our Site, Google AdWords allows us to advertise to you following your visit. This could be in the form an advertisement on the Google search results page, or a website in the Google Display Network. Any data collected will be used in accordance with this policy and Google’s privacy policy. By visiting the [Google Ad Settings page](https://www.google.com/settings/ads), you can set your preferences for how Google advertises to you, or alternatively, you can opt-out of interest-based adverting entirely by revisiting your cookie settings.

We use cookies to personalize or enhance your user experience and to facilitate the tracking of session and cross session activities. A cookie is a small text file that is placed on your hard disk by a web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. For example, if you personalize a web page, or navigate within a site, a cookie helps the site to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. Hence, this simplifies the process of delivering relevant content and eases site navigation by providing and saving your preferences and login information as well as providing personalized functionality.

The type of information that may be stored in a cookie includes non-PII about you. Some examples may include a randomly assigned user or session identification number, the country where you are located, and your first name to welcome you back to the site.

We reserve the right to share aggregated site statistics with third parties, but will not allow other companies to place cookies on our website unless there is a temporary, overriding customer value (such as merging into our Site another site that relies on third-party cookies).

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies. If you reject cookies by changing your browser settings then be aware that this may affect the functionality of our Site.

#### _D. Customer Service:_

We also collect information when you interact with our Customer Care Call Center in order to appropriately track, research and respond to member inquiries.

#### _E. One Twine Use_

As a Recyclebank Member, you will have the ability to access, use and transact on One Twine. We collect all use and transactional information on One Twine in keeping with this Policy and One Twine's Privacy Policy.

### 2\. Why Does Recyclebank Collect Information About You and How Do We Use It?

Recyclebank uses the information described above to provide you with a superior member experience and, as necessary, to administer our business through the Recyclebank Rewards Program.  For example, we collect various types of information that allow us to: ****

  * reward Members in our Rewards Program for certain activities including recycling and other environmentally conscious activities ( _e.g._ we may use household recycling data and PII to determine how many Recyclebank Reward Points you have earned, to alert you when you earn Reward Points and to fulfill reward requests);
  * provide a more personalized online experience by using the images and screen names that you upload to the Site or select to identify you, both to yourself and to other participants ( _e.g._ this may include us publicly displaying on our Site your photo and user name in connection with your profile and activities in the Recyclebank Reward Program); 
  * authenticate your identity; 
  * promote partners and vendors who support our various programs which comprise the Reward Program;
  * conduct research and perform analysis in order to measure, maintain, protect, develop, and improve services to members ( _e.g._ aggregate recycling and redemption data and other member actions from Recyclebank participants); 
  * administer sweepstakes, contests, promotions, or surveys; and 
  * communicate with you about special offers, events, new products or services, or surveys.

### 3\. Who Does Recyclebank Share Your Information With and Why?

Recyclebank is not in the business of selling your information.  We consider this information to be a vital part of our relationship with you.  There are, however, certain circumstances in which we may share your PII with certain third parties with or without further notice to you, as set forth below:

  1. _With your Consent_ : We may share or disclose your PII or program activity with third parties with your express consent. Should an event arise which we deem appropriate to obtain your express consent, we will contact you directly using the contact information we have on file for you. It is important that you maintain all your information with us current and accurate.
  2. _Law and Harm_ : We may disclose your PII if we are required to comply with a law, regulation or legal request; to protect the safety of any of our Site users, any person or the general public; to address fraud, security or technical issues; or to protect Recyclebank's rights or property.
  3. _Business Transfers_ : If Recyclebank or all or substantially all of its assets are sold to a third party or parties, we may transfer Recyclebank members' PII and other information to those parties as part of the transaction. In the event of such a transaction, we will make sure that the acquiring entities are bound by the terms of this Privacy Policy.
  4. _Service Providers_ : Recyclebank, like many businesses, sometimes hires other companies to perform certain business-related functions (e.g. mailing campaigns to customers, maintaining databases, processing payments, and processing purchases). When we employ the services of another company to perform a function of this nature, we only provide them with the information that they need to perform their specific function(s) and require that they in turn gain access only after agreeing to maintain this information in confidentiality and use it only for the limited purpose of providing the services contracted by Recyclebank.
  5. _Advertisers_ : We may provide aggregate anonymous information concerning member usage of our Site to third parties, such as in the case of advertisers, for purposes we deem, in our sole discretion, to be appropriate regarding our Rewards Program.
  6. _Recycling Programs/Non-Personal Aggregate Data_ : In order to participate in any of our Recycling Programs, Recyclebank may record household recycling habits, redemption habits, and other information about you associated with our Recycling Programs. For example, we may record the frequency with which you recycle and the weight or volume of the materials you recycle. Occasionally in the United States, we may disclose individual level data corresponding to your address and location as well as aggregate recycling data to municipalities and haulers upon request if we determine this information will benefit the general public, promote further green actions within communities or if we are contractually obligated to do so as part of providing the Recycling Program in that community.

### 4\. How Can You Change Your Privacy Preferences or Account Information? 

If, at any point during your membership with Recyclebank, you decide that you do not wish to receive specific program notices or messages, you can update your account profile and communication preferences at any time through the Site or by contacting Recyclebank's Customer Care Call Center as indicated below under “Contact Us”

We encourage you to keep your information with us current and up to date. You can make corrections, updates or deletions to your account information by accessing your online profile and visiting the “Account” Section of the Site. ****

### 5\. **What Information Is Collected Through Integration With Third Party Services?**

 **

  1. _Social Networking Sites:_ One of the special features of this Site and the Recyclebank Rewards Programs is that we enable you to log in to your online profile with us via various online third party services, such as social media and social networking services like Facebook and Twitter.  By directly integrating our services with other online third party services, we make your online experience richer and more personalized. To take advantage of this feature we will ask you to log in to the relevant social networking service. When you add any social networking service to your Recyclebank online profile or log into this Site through your other social networking account(s), Recyclebank will collect relevant information necessary to enable this Site to access and collect your data contained within that particular social networking service ( _e.g._ such as your Facebook profile information). Please remember however that the manner in which such third party social network provider uses, stores and discloses your information is governed solely by that provider's policies, and Recyclebank will have no liability or responsibility for the privacy practices or other actions of any third party site or provider that you may enable and link to your online experience with Recyclebank.
  2. _Recyclebank Rewards Program Sponsors_ : A key component of the Rewards Program is the member being able to earn and redeem Reward Points with featured sponsors. These featured sponsors are linked to our Rewards Program both outside and through our Site and integrated into member accounts to allow for maximum member ease in both earning and redeeming Rewards Points. This integration of featured sponsors does include Recyclebank making available certain aggregated member information which is anonymous as to any specific member. This allows Recyclebank to continue to incentivize members to engage in its Rewards Program while also maintaining individual member PII confidentiality.

### 6\. Third Party Links and Websites:

This Privacy Policy applies only to the Site and Recyclebank services, which includes One Twine. This Site and e-mails received from Recyclebank may contain advertisements for and links to other websites not operated or controlled by Recyclebank.  The policies and procedures we describe here do not apply to those third party sites.  The links to third party websites available on this Site or in any e-mails sent to you by Recyclebank do not imply that Recyclebank endorses or has reviewed those third party sites. We suggest contacting those sites directly for information on their privacy policies.

### 7\. Are There Any Other Issues To Consider?

Recyclebank takes all reasonable and appropriate steps to protect all information received from our members and provided via our Site and programs from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction. However, no Internet or e-mail transmission is ever fully secure or error free.  In particular, e-mail sent to or from this Site may not be secure. Therefore, you should take special care in deciding what information you send to us via e-mail. Please keep this in mind when disclosing any information to Recyclebank via the Internet.  You are also responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your unique password and account information and for controlling access to your e-mail communications at all times.  Further, the security of the PII that we collect is of the utmost importance to us. We take all commercially reasonable steps to secure your PII. Reasonable physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard the information we collect has been implemented and is updated periodically as we deem necessary. With this in mind, we limit access to PII to only those employees and contractors who need access in order to perform their duties.

### 8\. Updates to the Privacy Policy

The Site and our Rewards Program may change from time to time.  As a result, it may be necessary for Recyclebank to make changes to this Privacy Policy.  We reserve the right to update this Privacy Policy at any time, with or without advance notice. In the event there are significant changes in the manner in which we maintain and treat PII or the terms of this Privacy Policy, we will display a notice on our Site or send you an email to inform you of these changes. If you object to this Privacy Policy or to any future update of this policy or no longer wish to participate in the Recyclebank Rewards Program, you may close your account by contacting us. Unless otherwise stated, this Privacy Policy applies to all the information we possess about you and your membership with Recyclebank.  This Privacy Policy was last updated on the date indicated below.  We encourage you to periodically review this Privacy Policy to stay informed about how we are helping to protect the PII we receive from you. Your continued use of this Site or participation in any of the programs Recyclebank offers shall constitute your agreement to this Privacy Policy and any of its updates.

**

### **9.** **Contact Us**

 **

Should you have any questions or comments about our Privacy Policy, please contact us at:

_E-mail_ : [privacy@recyclebank.com](mailto:privacy@recyclebank.com)

_Toll Free (US) Call_ :  
1-888-727-2978 

_International Call_ :  
212-659-9900 

_Postal_ :  
RecycleRewards, Inc.  
Legal Department  
443 Park Avenue South, 9th Floor  
New York, NY 10016 

**
